let's see it wait my signatures not on
it how can it be the Gavin Belson's
signature box 3 without Gavin Belson's
signature on it what's wrong with that
well gene do you have the report
absolutely pleasure to be on your team
Kevin here it is the signature displayed
troubling traits left of upright slant
narrow angles 10 strokes conclusively
indicative of sociopathic tendencies
what characterized by a lack of empathy
and need to dominate a willingness to
hurt others to achieve ones goals
inability to accept bad news hoover sir
get this horrible woman the out of
my office now
I don't like it it's just so edgy Banksy
is a very edgy artist the edgiest what
is this Banksy is insisting his
signature should be on his work this is
supposed to be my signature on what
planet does a signature have a signature
on it you know what Banksy we're on
a campus full of literally thousands of
the greatest creative minds in the world
lets's crowdsource it with our employees
we'll make it a contest people will feel
empowered and part of the team and it
won't cost us you see this is what
a benevolent leader does make it happen
this one came in third with 46 votes q
next this one came in second with 374
votes
nice feels solid and with nine thousand
nine hundred and eighty six votes this
by far was Julie's favorite
hmm I like it it's bold
Gavin be the box three Signature Edition
I put my name on this because I
personally stand behind the new SAS /
SSD slash nvme drive bays the 24 core
processors I stand behind the ECC ddr4
sdram lrdimms
and their exceptional reliability will
you stand with me
[Music]
you